makeuseof.com 2019-06-29

# Privacy Policy and Affiliate Disclaimer

## Privacy Policy

If you’d like to withdraw consent and adjust your privacy options, click here to open the consent management window again.

Thank you for reading _makeuseof.com_.

Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.

On our website, we run several third-party services and use cookies to optimise your browsing experience.

**Cookies**  
Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your web browser (if you allow) that enables the site’s or service provider’s systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

We use cookies to understand and save user’s preferences for future visits.

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser settings. Since browser is a little different, look at your browser’s Help Menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.

If you turn cookies off, some of the features that make your site experience more efficient may not function properly.

**Google Analytics**  
We use Google Analytics to track and analyze our web traffic. **We do not have access to the information collected by Google** apart from what is displayed in our Google Analytics portal.

We have implemented the following data collection features in Google Analytics:

1\. Remarketing with Google AdSense

> Enables data collection for Display and Search Remarketing. This includes data from Google’s signed-in users who have chosen to enable Google to associate their web and app browsing history with their Google account, and to use such information from their Google account to personalize ads. Google Analytics temporarily joins these identifiers to your Google Analytics data in order to support your audiences. When you enable this setting, you must adhere to the Google Analytics Advertising Features Policy, including rules around sensitive categories and the necessary privacy disclosures to your end users about the data you collect and share with Google.

2\. Advertising Reporting Features

> Enables Advertising Reporting features like Audience Demographics and Interests Reporting, DoubleClick Campaign Manager reporting, DoubleClick Bid Manager reporting, and Google Display Network Impression Reporting that help you better understand your users.

The information collected by Google may be linked to your Google account if you’re signed in. Google may also collect information relating to your:

  * browsing device;
  * location;
  * operating system.

Please read Google’s Privacy Policy for more information on how your data is collected and used: <https://policies.google.com/privacy>

To opt out of Google’s data collection, you may also set your browser to block all cookies, including cookies associated with our services.

**Google Adsense**  
We display advertisement powered by Google Adsense. Google Adsense uses the information Google collects to display the most useful ads online. When you’re signed in to your Google Account, they will also collect information that they store with your Google account. **We do not have access to any data collected by Google** for the purposes of advertising.

You may choose to opt out of personalised advertisements by disabling cookies.

**Parse.ly**  
We use Parse.ly to keep track of our web traffic statistics. All data collected by Parse.ly are anonymized.

> All the data that we do collect is de-identified. For example, our repeat visitor analytics is based on anonymous, randomized universally unique identifiers (aka UUIDs) that are stored on a per-site basis, and are not linked with any personally identifiable information. Further, the automatic collection of some web browser data, such as IP Addresses and Third-Party Cookies, can be explicitly disabled by customers

For more information on how Parse.ly collect and retain non-identifiable data, please read: <https://www.parse.ly/privacy-policy/>

**Gleam**  
We use Gleam to power our giveaways. Any data that Gleam collects requires user consent which involves filling in a form or connecting your Facebook account to Gleam. Some campaigns may also require additional identifiable fields that you may have to fill out.

When you connect your Gleam account with your social network account, you are allowing Gleam access to your information stored on your social account.

Gleam may also use cookies to identify if you’re logged into Gleam, track user referrals, etc.

For more information on how Gleam uses the data that they collect, please read <https://gleam.io/privacy>

**WordPress comments**  
If you choose to comment on our site, you will be asked to provide a name and email address. The data which you provide and your comment will be stored on our server along with your public IP address.

### Email/newsletter

When subscribing to our email newsletter, you may be asked to enter your name and/or email address or other details to help you with your experience.

As a newsletter subscriber, we keep a record of your IP address, the emails you open, and the links you click within those emails, so that we can more accurately recommend content, occasional third party offers and products that you might find valuable.

Any personal information you provide to us, including and similar to your name and e-mail address will not be released, sold, or rented to any entities or individuals outside of _makeuseof.com_. However, if you participate in a competition, your email address might be provided to the relevant vendor for registration/activation and ongoing support purposes.

We will **never** ask for credit card details and request that you do not enter them on any of the forms on _makeuseof.com_.

**To remove your data from our email server, simply unsubscribe through any one of our emails.**

**Advertising in emails**  
We, or a data provider we have engaged, may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser to enable you to receive customized ads, content or services.

No personally identifiable information is placed into these cookies. The cookies may reflect de-identified demographic or other data linked to data you voluntarily have submitted to us, e.g., your email address, in hashed, non-human readable form.

To opt-out of these cookies or learn more please go to <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>.

### Mobile applications

If you use our apps, you may be asked to register with your phone number or email address.

**obliviate**  
None of the data provided to us in obliviate will be shared with third parties.

obliviate will request permission to access your contact list in order to identify other obliviate users and allow you to establish connections with them. We will not use your contact list information for any other purpose.

obliviate will record your public IP address for logging purposes. We store the last two IP addresses used.

obliviate will request permission to access your personal media, including but not limited to the photo gallery, camera, and microphone. This is required for the purposes of attaching media to messages within the app. We do not store your personal media on our servers and will not use them for any other purpose.

Your phone number is required for registration. Messages within obliviate are routed by your phone number. We will not use your phone number for any other purpose.

**NeedHave**  
None of the data provided to us in NeedHave will be shared with third parties.

NeedHave will request permission to access your contact list in order to identify other NeedHave users and allow you to establish connections with them. We will not use your contact list information for any other purpose.

NeedHave will record your public IP address for logging purposes. We store the last two IP addresses used.

NeedHave will request permission to access your personal media, including but not limited to the photo gallery, camera, and microphone. This is required for the purposes of attaching media to listings within the app. We will not use them for any other purpose.

Your phone number is required for registration. Messages within NeedHave are routed by your phone number. We will not use your phone number for any other purpose.

NeedHave will request permission to access your location in order to display needs in your vicinity. Your location will only be used in the the app.

**Washie**  
None of the data provided to us in Washie will be shared with third parties.

Washie will utilize your public IP address in order to identify your location and present you with the local weather forecast. Your IP address or location will not be used for any other purpose.

**PolyTime**  
None of the data provided to us in PolyTime will be shared with third parties.

PolyTime will utilize your public IP address in order to identify your location and present you with the local time. Your IP address or location will not be used for any other purpose.

### Third-party disclosure

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your Personally Identifiable Information unless we provide users with advance notice. This does not include website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or serving our users, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release information when it’s release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others’ rights, property or safety.

However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

**Third-party links**  
Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third-party products or services on our website or in our newsletter. These third-party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

**California Online Privacy Protection Act**  
CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law’s reach stretches well beyond California to require any person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting Personally Identifiable Information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals or companies with whom it is being shared. – See more at: <http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf>

**According to CalOPPA, we agree to the following:**  
Users can visit our site anonymously.

Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our home page or as a minimum, on the first significant page after entering our website.

Our Privacy Policy link includes the word ‘Privacy’ and can easily be found on the page specified above.

You will be notified of any Privacy Policy changes on our Privacy Policy Page.

You can change your personal information by logging in to your account.

**How does our site handle Do Not Track signals?**  
We honor Do Not Track signals and Do Not Track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.

**Does our site allow third-party behavioral tracking?**  
It’s also important to note that we allow third-party behavioral tracking

**COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)**  
When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under the age of 13 years old, the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, United States’ consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children’s privacy and safety online.

We do not specifically market to children under the age of 13 years old.

**Fair Information Practices**  
The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.

In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur we will notify you via email within 7 business days.

We also agree to the Individual Redress Principle which requires that individuals have the right to legally pursue enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or government agencies to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors.

**CAN SPAM Act**  
The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations.

We collect your email address in order to send information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions

To be in accordance with CANSPAM, we agree to the following:

  * Not use false or misleading subjects or email addresses.
  * Identify the message as an advertisement in some reasonable way.
  * Include the physical address of our business or site headquarters.
  * Monitor third-party email marketing services for compliance, if one is used.
  * Honor opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly.
  * Allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email.

If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, follow the instructions at the bottom of each email and we will promptly remove you from ALL correspondence.

Last updated: 21 September 2018

**Contacting Us**  
If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy, you may contact us using the information below.

_makeuseof.com_  
1405 Bonham Strand Trade Centre, 135 Bonham Strand  
Sheung Wan, Hong Kong 000000  
Hong Kong  
contact@makeuseof.com

## Affiliate Disclaimer

We love researching and reviewing stuff, then sharing our findings with you. And you can help us keep the lights on.

You may have noticed that we often use Amazon links when recommending products. We’re consumers too – often, our review products are purchased from Amazon. So if you do decide to use our links to purchase a product we’re recommending, then we get paid a small commission, and in turn, you’ll shop with confidence knowing that Amazon will deliver your product safely.

You’ll also be glad to know that our recommendations are always based on the merits of the items. As you can tell from our product review conclusions, we always provide advice on whether a product is worth purchasing. We would never recommend anything we wouldn’t buy ourselves.

You’ll also notice that we use iTunes affiliate links where appropriate. Rest assured, these affiliate links do not affect you in any way. They will, however, share a small portion of the sale with us. These links are always added after the article or review is written. We won’t publish a biased review for the sole purpose of profiting from affiliate sales. That goes against our principles.

We use [Amazon Associates](https://affiliate-program.amazon.com/) and VigLink to retroactively and automatically convert eligible links. You can [opt out of Viglink](http://www.viglink.com/opt-out), if you wish.

Some of our Best Of lists also contain affiliate links. Notable ones include our [Best Web Hosting Services](https://www.makeuseof.com/tag/best-web-hosting-services/) and [Best VPN Service Providers](https://www.makeuseof.com/tag/best-vpn-services/). These pages were created with our readers in mind, and therefore, we only recommend the best apps and services. Affiliate links were inserted only as an afterthought, which again, pays us a very small compensation if you do decide to buy or sign up for a service. These links also appear in individual review articles.

And now, some legal stuff:

Disclosure of Material Connection: Some of the links on MakeUseOf.com are “affiliate links.” This means if you click on the link and purchase the item, we will receive an affiliate commission. Regardless, we only recommend products or services we believe will add value to our readers. We also receive compensation for sponsored posts and emails.We are disclosing this in accordance with the Federal Trade Commission’s [16 CFR, Part 255](https://www.ftc.gov/policy/federal-register-notices/guides-concerning-use-testimonials-advertising-16-cfr-part-255): “Guides Concerning the Use of Endorsements and Testimonials in Advertising.”

### A quick word regarding sponsored articles, manuals and giveaways

Whenever a company contracts us to write about their product in the form of a review, manual or giveaway, in exchange for compensation, we will always disclose that fact in the published work. We only choose to partner with high-quality clients in order to preserve our reputation. At the same time, we try to be as honest as possible, ensuring that our readers receive the most truthful information about the apps and services we review. Therefore, you have nothing to worry about — sponsored articles, manuals and giveaways are written by the same people who publish regular, non-sponsored articles, and contains the same advice we’d normally dish out. We do not discriminate.
